A Guide to the Diana Lee-Smith Architectural Papers, 1966-1991
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Diana Lee-Smith Architectural Papers, 1966-1991
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1990-005
0.4 cu. ft. 1 box
British architect and planner living in Nairobi, Kenya. Projects focus on housing and shelter concerns in Africa. This collection consists of a number of papers, publications, books and magazines that were written or edited by Diana Lee-Smith.
Lee-Smith, Diana
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Diana Lee-Smith Architectural Papers were donated to the International Archive of Women in Architecture at Virginia Tech by the creator in July 1991.
Biographical Note
Diana Lee-Smith is British architect and planner living in Nairobi, Kenya. Born in Reading, England (1940), she received her diploma of the Architectural Association, London, UK in 1964. She has had numerous academic appointments around the world including Kenya, the United States, and Canada. She holds a doctorate in Architecture and Development Studies and has written extensively on urban poverty, gender, development, and environmental issues.
Lee-Smith was one of the founders of the Mazingira Institute, an independent research and development NGO, an institution that carried out the first survey of urban agriculture in Kenya (1985). She has served as a consultant on a number of projects focusing on African housing and shelter concerns.
Scope and Content Note
Collection consists of Mazingira Institute publications edited by Lee-Smith including: public health magazines for children, SINA (Settlements Information Network Africa) Newsletters, a curriculum vitae, and articles and speeches by and about Lee-Smith.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Architects and community; International Archive of Women in Architecture (IAWA)
Contents List
- Curriculum Vitae and Writings,1966-1990 (Box-folder 1:1)
- Newsclipping,1973 (Box-folder 1:2)
- Mazingira Institute Publications, Edited by Lee-Smith,1980-1987 (Box-folder 1:3)
  Contents:
  - Uses of Trees and Shrubs Identified by Rural Children in Kenya, 1980
  - Training Human Settlements Workers in Eastern and Southern Africa, 1981
  - Community Participation in Human Settlements, 1983
  - Zimbabwe National Workshop on Construction and Housing Cooperatives, 1987
- Rainbow Magazine for Children, a Mazingira Institute publication,1981-1984 (Box-folder 1:4)
- SINA (Settlements Information Network Africa) Newsletter, Edited by Lee-Smith,1982-1991 (Box-folder 1:5)
- The Mazingira Institute Magazine for Children,1986-1989 (Box-folder 1:6)
- NGOs and Shelter, Published by SINA,1987 (Box-folder 1:7)
- Institution Development for Delivery of Low-Income Housing: An evaluation of Dandora Community Development Project in Nairobi,1988 (Box-folder 1:8)
- HIC Women and Shelter Network Newsletter, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 1:9)
- Book: Environment and Urbanization, vol. 3, no.2 [has a profile on HIC Women in Shelter Network],1991 (Box-folder 1:10)